{"Topic": "Defence (2 pages)", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "From which of the following countries has India purchased the Pilatus PC-7 trainer aircraft", "op1": "United States of America", "op2": "France", "op3": "Switzerland", "op4": "Germany", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Admiral Gorshkov, the Soviet aircraft carrier imported by India is now named -", "op1": "INS Vikrant", "op2": "INS Vikramaditya", "op3": "INS Virat", "op4": "INS Vishaal", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following organizations has Sarvatra Sarvottam Suraksha as its slogan?", "op1": "Border Security Forece", "op2": "Sikh Light Infantry", "op3": "Indian Air Force", "op4": "National Security Guard", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is the Heavy Vehicles Factory located?", "op1": "Kanpur", "op2": "Khadki", "op3": "Avadi", "op4": "24 Paraganas", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the following places was a new Officers' Training Academy for training Army officers established in 2011?", "op1": "Pune", "op2": "Jabalpur", "op3": "Secunderabad", "op4": "Gaya", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following aircraft is the air-to-air refueller of the Indian Air Force?", "op1": "C \u2013 17 Globemaster", "op2": "IIyushin - 76", "op3": "IIyushin - 78", "op4": "C \u2013 130J Hercules", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is India\u2019s first indigenously developed nuclear powered submarine?", "op1": "INS Vikrant", "op2": "INS Trikhand", "op3": "INS Arihant", "op4": "INS Sindhurakshak", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following is the only Chief of Air Staff to be given the rank of Marshall of the Indian Air Force?", "op1": "Arjan Singh", "op2": "Subroto Mukherjee", "op3": "P.C. Lal", "op4": "O.P. Mehra", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Indra series of exercises are jointly held biennially in the Indian Ocean by India and -", "op1": "Russia", "op2": "France", "op3": "Singapore", "op4": "Israel", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following corps deals with the supply of weaponry and ammunition to the Indian Army?", "op1": "Army Ordnance Corps", "op2": "Armoured Corps", "op3": "Army Supply Corps", "op4": "Corps of EME", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is home base of the aircraft carrier INS Vikramaditya?", "op1": "Visakhapatnam", "op2": "Cochin", "op3": "Karwar", "op4": "Jamnagar", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is the Headquarters of South Western Air Command located?", "op1": "Vadodara", "op2": "Jodhpur", "op3": "Pune", "op4": "Gandhinagar", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the equivalent rank in Army of the Naval rank of Captain?", "op1": "Colonel", "op2": "Brigadier", "op3": "Major", "op4": "Captain", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the Chief of Army at the time of Indo-Pak war of 1971?", "op1": "General PP Kumaramangalam", "op2": "Field Marshall SHFJ Manekshaw", "op3": "General JN Chaudhari", "op4": "General KS Thimayya", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following was the first aircraft inducted by the Indian Air Force (then Royal Indian Air Force) in 1932?", "op1": "de Havilland Tiger Moth", "op2": "Westland Wapiti", "op3": "Supermarine Spitfire", "op4": "Fairchild Packet", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The biennial joint multi-nation Naval exercise held in the Indian Ocean is named \u2013(The exercise was recently held in February 2014)", "op1": "Yudh Abhyas", "op2": "Malabar", "op3": "Milan", "op4": "Shoorveer", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the first recipient of the Param Vir Chakra, gallantry award?", "op1": "Lance Naik Albert Ekka", "op2": "Havildar Abdul Hamid", "op3": "Major Shaitan Singh", "op4": "Major Somnath Sharma", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Lt Commander Abhilash Tomy of the Indian Navy became the first Indian to complete a solo, unassisted, non-stop circumnavigation of the world in 2013. What was the name of the vessel used by him?", "op1": "INSV Mandovi", "op2": "INSV Mhadei", "op3": "INS Abhimanyu", "op4": "INS Abhay", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is the Indian National Defence University being set up?", "op1": "Medak, Andhra Pradesh", "op2": "Amethi, Uttar Pradesh", "op3": "Gurgaon, Haryana", "op4": "Kasargod, Kerala", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is the College of Defence Management located?", "op1": "Dehradun", "op2": "Pune", "op3": "Secunderabad", "op4": "Chennai", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What was the name given to the operation conducted by National Security Guard in 2008 against terrorist attack in Taj hotel, Mumbai?", "op1": "Operation Black Tornado", "op2": "Operation Black Thunder", "op3": "Operation Safed Sagar", "op4": "Operation Vijay", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "At which of the following places is the headquarters of a Naval Command NOT located?", "op1": "Mumbai", "op2": "Goa", "op3": "Kochi", "op4": "Visakhapatnam", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "On which of the following dates is the Navy Day celebrated in India?", "op1": "January 15", "op2": "October 8", "op3": "December 4", "op4": "February 1", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In 2013, the Indian Navy inducted the Boeing P-8I Aircraft at Naval Station, Rajali. To serve what purpose the aircraft has been inducted?", "op1": "Long Range Maritime Reconnaissance", "op2": "Transport of troops from ships to bases and vice versa", "op3": "VIP movements of President and other dignitaries", "op4": "Training of Naval pilots", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one among the following is the unit raised to protect the naval assets?", "op1": "Sagar Rakshak Bal", "op2": "Sagar Suraksha Bal", "op3": "Sagar Prahari Bal", "op4": "Sagar Nigrani Bal", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Indian Military Training Team (IMTRAT) imparts training to army officers of", "op1": "Nepal", "op2": "Bangladesh", "op3": "Maldives", "op4": "Bhutan", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Indian Army\u2019s counter-insurgency school is situated in", "op1": "Kanker", "op2": "Srinagar", "op3": "Tezpur", "op4": "Vairengte", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Dhanush, a missile inducted into the Indian Navy", "op1": "is a customized and naval variant of Prithvi missile", "op2": "has a range of 700  km", "op3": "can be launched from an aircraft", "op4": "cannot carry nuclear warheads", "Answer": 2}]}